In After Please adjust equipment.
二零二三年广东省初中学业水平考试
英语试卷听力部分。
首先播放两分钟的音乐信号，
请监考老师调试好播音。
设备的音量。
音乐结束后，听力考试正式开始
嗯。
Please volume equipment.
视听到此结束。
一，听说应用。
听句子，请根据所听内容
选择符合题意的图画，回答问题，并将答题卡上对应题目所选的选项涂黑
of The boy is playing the guitar.
每个句子听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五秒钟的答题时间。
The boy is playing the guitar.
2. Hurry up!
It's 7.45 now.
Hurry up! It's 7.45 now.
3. Tom is a famous doctor in the Tom is a famous doctor in the city.
4. Look! There is a teapot on the
Look! There is a teapot on the
5. Mary was 1 Mary was 1.6 meters tall last year.
点六米高。
去年，
逼听对话，请根据每段对话的内容回答问题。
从每小题所给的三个选项中
选出一个最佳答案，并将答题卡上对应题目所选的选项涂黑。
每段对话听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟。
时间阅读题目。
每一小题听完后，你有五秒钟的答题时间。
听第一段对话，回答第六小题。
how will you go to the museum tomorrow?
John, will take a bath there.
I will take a bath
听第二段对话，回答第七小题。
Sam, what's your favorite subject?
I like geography best.
It is great fun.
Sam, what's your favorite subject?
like geography best.
It is great fun.
听第三段对话，回答第
Listen the Listen to question.
八小题。
Listen to Madam, may I take your order?
听第四段对话，回答第九小题。
I'd like two glasses of lemon juice, please.
Madam, may I take your order?
听第五段对话。
Answer the tenth question.
Listen to the fifth
Hi, Lisa. Where are you going for your holiday?
I plan to go to the mountains.
听第六段对话，回答第十一至十二小题。
may I go outside to play now?
Have you got your housework down, dear?
What is my work today?
I washed my clothes yesterday.
Well, tidy up your bedroom then.
Okay, I will do it right away.
Mom, may I go outside to play now?
Have you got your housework down, dear?
What is my work today?
I washed my clothes yesterday.
Well, tidy up your bedroom then.
Okay, I will do it right away.
听第七段对话，回答第十三至十五小题。
Listen Hi, I decide to buy flowers for him.
How about you?
Well, I want to buy him a box of chocolates.
Do you think that will be okay?
Hmm, he doesn't like sweet food very much.
Perhaps you can buy him some books instead.
Hmm, I will go to the bookstore and have a look.
Hi, Kelly. What gift have you prepared for Ben's birthday?
Hi, Tony. I decide to buy flowers for him.
How about you?
Well, I want to buy him a box of chocolates.
Do you think that will be okay?
I okay? Hmm, he doesn't like sweet food very much.
Perhaps you can buy him some books instead.
Okay, I will go to the bookstore and have a look.
C. Frank is a primary school student.
听短文，请根据所听内容，从每一小题所给的三个选项中
选出一个最佳答案，并将答题卡上对。
命题目所选的选项涂黑。
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
One day his class went on trip to a zoo.
When they got there, they were very happy.
There were so many kinds of such as bears and so on.
went to see the monkeys first with his friends.
When he was taking photos at the monkey hill, it started to So the students ran
everywhere to find a place to keep out of the rain.
Soon Frank got wet and he was cold.
What was worse, he got lost.
Just as he was about to cry, he saw an old building.
He quickly got into it and met a zookeeper there.
The zookeeper found some dry clothes for Finally, with her help, found his way back
to the monkey hill.
Frank is a primary school student.
One day his class went on trip to a zoo.
When they got there, they were very happy.
There were so many kinds of animals, such as tigers, bears and so on.
Frank went to see the monkeys first with his friends.
When he was taking photos at the monkey hill, it started to So the students ran
everywhere to find a place to keep out of the rain.
Soon Frank got wet and he was cold.
What was worse, he got lost.
Just as he was about to cry, he saw an old building.
He quickly got into it and met a zookeeper there.
The zookeeper found some dry clothes for him.
Finally, with her help, Frank found his way back to the monkey hill.
第听填信息：你将听到一则烹饪比赛的通知，
请根据所听内容填写下面的信息卡，并将答案写在答题卡对应题目的答题
位置上。
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
Good morning, class.
Here is some good news for you if you love cooking.
Our school is going to hold a cooking competition next Monday in the school dining
hall. Vegetables, eggs, meat and other necessary things will be provided.
After you finish your cooking, some teachers will give scores to your dishes
according to how good they look, smell and taste and how healthy they are.
If you are lucky enough to be one of the top 20, you will get a to take a free
cooking lesson at a top restaurant.
What a great chance to show your skills and creativity.
If you are interested, please let me know before this Friday.
Thank you. Good morning, class.
Here is some good news for you if you love cooking.
Our school is going to hold a cooking competition next Monday in the school dining
hall. Vegetables, eggs, meat and other necessary things will be provided.
After you finish your cooking, some teachers will give scores to your dishes
according to how good they look, smell and taste and how healthy they are.
If you are lucky enough to be one of the top 20,
you will get a to take a free cooking lesson at a top restaurant.
What a great chance to show your skills and creativity.
If you are interested, please let me know before this Friday.
Thank you. This is
听力理解部分到此结束。